Then we worship Gauri, that is the Kundalini,
Dan aanbidden we Gauri, dat is de Kundalini,
because through Kundalini only we get to our ascent.
want alleen door Kundalini komen we tot onze opstijging.
Kundalini is the power, residual power, of the Mahakali.
Kundalini is de kracht, restkracht, van Mahakali.
And She is settled in the triangular bone, as you know,
En ze is gevestigd in het driehoekige bot, zoals je weet,
and is worshipped as a “Kanya”, because though She is married, yet She’s a Virgin, so She’s worshipped there.
en wordt aanbeden als een "Kanya", want hoewel ze getrouwd is,
After that, the Kundalini has to rise through the central path of Sushumna
Daarna moet de Kundalini opstijgen via het centrale pad van Sushumna
which is guarded and nurtured by Mahalakshmi,
dat bewaakt en gevoed wordt door Mahalakshmi.
so we have to worship Mahalakshmi’s force, that’s how we worship Her.
Dus moeten we Mahalakshmi's kracht aanbidden, dat is hoe we haar aanbidden.
Through the Mahalakshmi we prepare the path for Kundalini to cross over.
Door de Mahalakshmi bereiden we het pad voor waarop Kundalini kan oversteken.
When the Kundalini crosses the Mahalakshmi path, it comes up to the Sahasrara
Wanneer de Kundalini het Mahalakshmi-pad kruist, komt ze omhoog naar de Sahasrara
and breaks the Brahmarandra, becoming One with the All Pervading Power of Shiva Tattva.
en breekt de Brahmarandra, waardoor ze één wordt met de alomtegenwoordige kracht van Shiva Tattva.
Because Sadashiva is on our fontanelle bone – is, His Legs are resting
Omdat Sadashiva op ons fontanelbot zit - dat wil zeggen, zijn benen rusten
on our fontanelle bone area.
op ons fontanelbotgebied.
When the Kundalini touches His feet,
Wanneer de Kundalini zijn voeten aanraakt,
then the Shiva Tattva in our heart, which is the Spirit, is enlightened and we get the enlightenment.
dan wordt de Shiva Tattva in ons hart, die de Spirit is, verlicht en krijgen we de verlichting.
This is the yoga which we achieve through our Sahaja system.
Dit is de yoga die we bereiken door ons Sahaja systeem.
And that is why we have now worshipped the Mahalakshmi.
En daarom hebben we nu de Mahalakshmi aanbeden.
After that, now we have to in… we have to invite, avahana as they call it, innovation;
Daarna moeten we in... we moeten uitnodigen, avahana zoals ze het noemen, vernieuwing,
invite the deity of Shiva and Parvati,
de Godheden Shiva en Parvati uitnodigen,
and then we have to put our hearts to pour its love,
en dan moeten we ons hart op de liefde storten,
which is called as “abhisheka”, through the symbol of water.
wat "abhisheka" wordt genoemd, door het symbool van water.
The… the water container is like a heart which pours the water all the time on the Feet,
De watercontainer is als een hart dat de hele tijd water giet op de voeten,
showing that it is our heart which is pouring our love on Shiva,
wat aantoont dat het ons hart is dat onze liefde uitstort op Shiva,
by which we win Him over and call Him, invite Him.
waardoor we hem voor ons winnen en hem roepen, hem uitnodigen.
And after that, we will give Him what He likes the most, is the Bel Patra,
En daarna geven we hem wat hij het liefste heeft, de Bel Patra,
which is a leaf which has got three leaves on one stem,
dat is een blad dat drie bladeren aan één steel heeft,
which means His three powers, Trigunatmika, three powers.
wat zijn drie krachten betekent, Trigunatmika, drie krachten.
So with our three powers, ours trigunas, our three powers,
Dus met onze drie krachten, onze triguna’s, onze drie krachten,
we surrender ourselves to Shiva and by that,
geven we onszelf over aan Shiva en daarmee
we show that we give our trigunas to You, so that we become gunateet.
tonen we dat we onze triguna’s aan u geven, zodat we gunateet worden.
This is what is the Shiva puja.
Dit is wat de Shiva Puja is.
May God bless you!
Moge God je zegenen!